Gertrude Berg Papers
Gertrude Berg Papers
1930-1962
Berg, Gertrude, 1899-1966.
99 linear ft.
Papers of the American Jewish radio and television actress; author, producer of The Goldbergs. Correspondence, clippings, and other material in scrapbooks; radio and television scripts for productions of The Goldbergs, House of Glass, Mrs. G. Goes to College, etc.; interviews and articles about Gertrude Berg.
148846
Biographical History
Mrs. Gertrude Berg was born in New York City on October 3, 1899, the daughter of Jacob and Diana Edelstein. She married Lewis Berg in 1918 and has 2 children, Cherney and Harriet. She first appeared in radio as actress-author-producer of the program The Goldbergs in 1929. She also wrote the program Kate Hopkins and was writer-producer of The House of Glass in 1935. Mrs. Berg was a collaborator on the film Make a Wish with Bobby Breen, and was Mollie in the film The Goldbergs. She appeared in the television series The Goldbergs and also in the series Mrs. G. Goes to College. She has appeared in the Broadway production of A Majority of One and also in summer stock productions. Mrs. Berg received the Antoinette Perry Award in 1959 and is the author of Molly and Me and Memoirs of Gertrude Berg.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Gertrude Berg Papers are divided into six series. The incoming Correspondence has been maintained in the scrapbooks established by the recipient; there is some overlapping of dates within the books, also some correspondence scrapbooks deal with specific subjects; scrapbooks include letters, cards, press clippings, magazines and other memorabilia. The correspondence covers a period from 1931 to 1961 and consists of ten books; the scrapbooks have been numbered for ease of access.
Subject file contains an autograph book, play programs, publicity, souvenir programs, and newspapers relating to Roosevelt.
General scrapbooks (1930-1957), are collections of press notices from newspapers, magazines, etc. related to Berg's professional activities, while Scrapbooks - specific subjects consist of material relating to paticular projects or productions. There is some overlapping of dates.
Radio and television scripts contains more than a thousand scripts from radio and television productions and spans more than thirty years. Individual scripts may consist of the original, typescripts, carbon copies, and mimeographed copies with revisions, or any combination thereof. The name of the program is given followed by the date of the script, whether it was daily, weekly, or a special show. The majority of the scripts are for The Goldbergs, House of Glass, and Mrs. G. Goes to College, but also included are special scripts and scripts dealing with special subjects (e.g., scripts for movies, plays, summer stock, interviews, and other subjects).
Published materials contains published materials by and about Gertrude Berg and covers the years from 1932-1960.
Arrangement of the Collection
The incoming Correspondence, in the scrapbooks established by the recipient, are arranged chronologically; there is some overlapping of dates within the books
The Subject file is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
General scrapbooks that cover a range of dates are arranged chronologically, while Scrapbooks - specific subjects are arranged alphabetically by topic.
Radio and television scripts are arranged chronologically within their respective years. Special scripts within a given year are arranged alphabetically after the regular scripts. Scripts dealing with special subjects are arranged alphabetically at the end of the series.
Published material is arranged alphabetically by title of the magazine in which it appeared.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radio, television, film; Popular culture; Women Authors; Berg, Gertrude, 1899-1966.; Berg, Gertrude, 1899-1966. -- Goldbergs.; Berg, Gertrude, 1899-1966. -- House of glass.; Berg, Gertrude, 1899-1966. -- Mrs. G. goes to college.; Actors -- United States.; Jewish actors.; Jews, American.; Radio authorship.; Radio programs.; Radio scripts.; Radio serials.; Television actors and actresses.; Television scripts.; United States -- Popular culture.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Interviews.; Programs (documents); Scrapbooks.; Scripts (documents); Actors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Gertrude E. Berg, 1965-1966.
Inventory
- Correspondence, 10 scrapbooks
  - Correspondence Scrapbook No. 1, 1931-1932 (Oversize 1)
  - Correspondence Scrapbook No. 2 (Special Letters), 1932-1954 (Box 57)
  - Correspondence Scrapbook No. 3, 1933-1934 (Oversize 2)
  - Correspondence Scrapbook No. 4, 1935 (Oversize 2)
  - Correspondence Scrapbook No. 5 (Special Letters and Church Letters), 1937-1953 (Box 57)
  - Correspondence Scrapbook No. 6, 1939-1941 (Oversize 18)
  - Correspondence Scrapbook No. 7, 1941-1949 (Box 57)
  - Correspondence Scrapbook No. 8, 1948-1950 (Box 57)
  - Correspondence Scrapbook No. 9 (Special Letters), 1953-1956; 1960-1961; includes folder with misc. correspondence from 1960-1961 (Box 57)
  - Correspondence Scrapbook No. 10: Israel, 1956 (Oversize 18)
- Subject files
  - Biographical (Box 1)
  - Autograph book (Box 1)
  - Play programs (Box 1)
  - Publicity publications
    - The Goldbergs (Box 1)
    - House of Glass (Box 1)
    - General (Box 1)
  - Souvenir programs, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - War newspapers, Roosevelt's speech and death (Box 2)
- General scrapbooks
  - General Scrapbook No. 1, 1930 (Box 58)
  - General Scrapbook No. 2, 1931-1932 (Oversize 3)
  - General Scrapbook No. 3, 1931-1932 (Box 58)
  - General Scrapbook No. 4, 1931-1932 (Box 58)
  - General Scrapbook No. 5, 1931-1933 (Oversize 3)
  - General Scrapbook No. 6, 1933 (Box 58)
  - General Scrapbook No. 7, 1933 (Box 58)
  - General Scrapbook No. 8, 1934 (Box 59)
  - General Scrapbook No. 9, 1934 (Box 59)
  - General Scrapbook No. 10, 1934-1935 (Box 59)
  - General Scrapbook No. 11, 1935 (Oversize 4)
  - General Scrapbook No. 12, 1935 (Box 59)
  - General Scrapbook No. 13, 1935 (Oversize 4)
  - General Scrapbook No. 14, 1935 (Oversize 5)
  - General Scrapbook No. 15, 1936 (Box 60)
  - General Scrapbook No. 16, 1936 (Oversize 5)
  - General Scrapbook No. 17, 1937 (Box 60)
  - General Scrapbook No. 18, 1937 (Box 60)
  - General Scrapbook No. 19, 1937-1938 (Box 61)
  - General Scrapbook No. 20, 1938-1939 (Box 61)
  - General Scrapbook No. 21, Aug 1939-Dec 1940 (Box 61)
  - General Scrapbook No. 22, 1941 (Oversize 6)
  - General Scrapbook No. 23, 1941-1947 (Oversize 6)
  - General Scrapbook No. 24, 1949-1950 (Oversize 6)
  - General Scrapbook No. 25, 1950 (Oversize 6)
  - General Scrapbook No. 26, 1950 (Oversize 6)
  - General Scrapbook No. 27, 1950 (Oversize 6)
  - General Scrapbook No. 28, 1950-1951 (Oversize 7)
  - General Scrapbook No. 29, 1950-1951 (Oversize 7)
  - General Scrapbook No. 30, 1950-1951 (Oversize 7)
  - General Scrapbook No. 31, 1950-1951 (Oversize 7)
  - General Scrapbook No. 32, 1950-1951 (Oversize 7)
  - General Scrapbook No. 33, 1950-1951 (Oversize 7)
  - General Scrapbook No. 34, 1950-1951 (Oversize 7)
  - General Scrapbook No. 35, 1951 (Oversize 7)
  - General Scrapbook No. 36, 1951 (Oversize 7)
  - General Scrapbook No. 37, 1951 (Oversize 7)
  - General Scrapbook No. 38, 1951-1952 (Oversize 8)
  - General Scrapbook No. 39, 1952 (Oversize 17)
  - General Scrapbook No. 40, 1953 (Oversize 8)
  - General Scrapbook No. 41, 1954-1957 (Oversize 9)
- Scrapbooks on specific subjects
  - Aprons (Subject Scrapbook No. 1), 1950-1959 (Box 62)
  - Arsenic and Old Lace (Subject Scrapbook No. 2), 1956 (Box 62)
  - Broadway Talks Back (Subject Scrapbook No. 3), 1946 (Oversize 17)
  - Cookbook (Subject Scrapbook No. 5), 1955 (Box 62)
  - The Goldbergs (comic strip) (Subject Scrapbook No. 4), 1944 (Oversize 10)
  - The Goldbergs (movie) (Subject Scrapbook No. 7), 1949-1951 (Oversize 10)
  - The Goldbergs (movie) (Subject Scrapbook No. 8), 1950-1951 (Oversize 17)
  - The Goldbergs (movie) (Subject Scrapbook No. 9), 1951 (Oversize 17)
  - The Goldbergs (TV show)
    - Publicity and Promotion (Vol. 1), 1949 (Oversize 11)
    - Station Cooperation (Vol. 2), 1949 (Oversize 12)
    - Network Cooperation [no volume number], 1949 (Oversize 13)
    - Publicity and Promotion (Vol. 3), 1949 (Oversize 14)
    - Publicity and Promotion (Vol. 4), 1949 (Oversize 15)
    - Publicity and Promotion (Vol. 5), 1949 (Oversize 16)
    - Misc. publicity stills (Oversize 17)
  - Guild films (Subject Scrapbook No. 6), 1955-1957 (Box 62)
  - Majority of One (play) (Subject Scrapbook No. 10), 1959 (Box 63)
  - Summer stock (Subject Scrapbook No. 12), 1956 (Box 63)
  - Summer stock (Subject Scrapbook No. 13), 1957 (Box 63)
  - Me and Molly (TV show) (Subject Scrapbook No. 14), 1948 (Box 63)
- Radio and T.V. Scripts, Total 1001
  - Scripts, 1929
    - Effie & Laura (Box 3)
  - Scripts, 1930
    - The Goldbergs (Box 3)
      Jan. 15
      Feb. 26
      March 19, 26
      April 2, 16, 23, 30
      May 7, 14
      July undated
      Sept. 19, 29
      Oct. 6, 27
      Nov. 3, 10, 17
      Dec. 1, 20, 27
  - Scripts, 1931
    - The Goldbergs (Box 3)
      Jan. 17
      Feb. 7, 14, 21, 28
      Mar. daily shows
      April daily shows
      May daily shows
      July daily shows
      Sept. daily shows
      Oct. daily shows
      Nov. daily shows
      Dec. daily shows
    - The Goldbergs, bound volumes, 1931 (Box 3)
      Episodes 79-104
      Episodes 105-130
      Episodes 131-156
      Episodes 183-208
      Episodes 209-234 (Jan. 20, 1932)
  - Scripts, 1932
    - The Goldbergs, bound volumes (Box 4)
      Episodes 235-260
    - The Goldbergs (Box 4)
      Jan. 1, 2, 4-9, 1-16, 18-23, 25-30
      Feb. 1-6, 8-13, 15-20, 22-27
      Mar. 1-6, 8-13, 15-19, 21-26, 28-31
      April 1-6, 8-13, 15-20, 22-27, 29-30
      May 2-16, 17-31
      June
      July 1-15, 16-31
      August 1-15
    - The Goldbergs (Box 5)
      August 16-31
      Sept. 1-8, 9-15, 16-21, 22-30
      Oct. 2-15 (original), 1-15, 17-31 (original), 17-31
      Nov. 1-18 (original), 1-18, 21-30 (original), 21-30
      Dec. 1-15, 15-31
  - Scripts, 1933
    - The Goldbergs (Box 6)
      Jan. 1-13, 16-31
      Feb. 1-15, 16-28
      Mar. 1-15, 16-31
      Apr. 3-14, 17-28
      May 1-16, 17-31
    - The Goldbergs (Box 7)
      June 1-15, 16-31
      July 3-14, 17-31
      Aug. 1-15, 16-31
      Sept. 1-15, 18-28
      Oct. 2-13, 16-31
    - The Goldbergs (Box 8)
      Nov. 1-17, 20-30
      Dec. 1-15, 18-29
  - Scripts, 1934
    - The Goldbergs (Box 8)
      Jan. 1-15, 16-31
      Feb. 1-16, 17-28
      Mar. 1-15, 16-30
      Apr. 2-16
    - The Goldbergs (Box 9)
      Apr. 17-30
      May 1-15, 17-31
      June 1-15, 18-28
      July 2-12
    - Special subjects (Box 9)
      Affairs of Molly, Episode 1-2
      Auditions - Hotel Hideway
      Mail – Letters re. Broadcasts
  - Scripts, 1935
    - House of Glass (Box 9)
      Apr. 17, 24
      May 1, 8, 15, 22, 29
      June 5, 12
    - House of Glass (Box 10)
      June 19, 26
      July 3, 10, 17, 24, 31
      Aug. 7, 14, 21, 28
      Sept. 4, 11, 18, 25
      Oct. 2, 9, 16, 23, 30
      Nov. 6, 13, 20, 27
      Dec. 4, 11
    - House of Glass (Box 11)
      Dec. 18, 25
    - Special subjects
      - Auditions (Box 11)
        Fifth Wheel, 1st & 2nd episodes
        Goldberg, Nov. 15
        House of Glass, March and April
        Ma Ma Talks, August 1
        Zeigfield, 1st & 2nd episodes
      - Mail, Breakdown of fan mail for House of Glass (Box 11)
  - Scripts, 1936
    - The Goldbergs (Box 11)
      Jan. 20-24, 27-31
      Feb. 3-7, 10-14, 17-21
    - The Goldbergs (Box 12)
      Feb. 24-28
      Mar. 2-6, 9-13, 16-20, 23-27, March 30-April 3
      Apr. 6-10, 13-17, 20-24, 27-May 1
    - The Goldbergs (Box 13)
      May 4-8, 11-15, 18-22, 25-29
      June 1-5, 8-12, 16-19, 22-26, 29-July 3
      July 6-10
    - Ma Ma Talks (Box 13)
      Jan. 22, 29
      Feb. 5-12, 19, 26
      March 4, 11, 18, 25
      April 1
    - Ma Ma Talks (Box 14)
      Apr. 8, 15, 22, 29
      May 6, 13, 20, 27
      June 3, 10, 17, 24
    - Special subjects
      - Auditions (Box 14)
        Aunt Libby - Oct. 27
        Goldberg, Colgate-Palmolive, Peet
        Goldbergs, Mr. Kesson Robbins - Sept.
        House of Glass, Dec. 8
      - Mail, Breakdown of fan mail (Box 14)
  - Scripts, 1937
    - The Goldbergs (Box 14)
      Sept. 13-17, 20-24, 27-Oct. 1
      Oct. 4-8, 11-15, 18-22, 25-29
      Nov. 1-5, 8-12, 15-19, 22-26
    - The Goldbergs (Box 15)
      Nov. 29-Dec. 3
      Dec. 6-10, 13-17
    - Special subjects (Box 15)
      Auditions - The Swinging Kid
  - Scripts, 1938
    - The Goldbergs (Box 15)
      Jan. 3-7, 10-14, 17-21, 24-28, 31-Feb. 4
      Feb. 7-11, 14-18, 21-25, 28-March 4
      Mar. 7-11, 14-18, 21-25, 28-Apr. 1
    - The Goldbergs (Box 16)
      Apr. 4-8, 11-15, 18-22, 25-29
      May 2-6, 9-13, 16-20, 23-27, 30-June 1
      June 6-10, 13-17, 20-24, 27-July 1
      July 4-8, 11-15, 18-22, 25-29
      Aug. 1-5, 8-12, 15-19
    - The Goldbergs (Box 17)
      Aug. 22-26, 29-Sept. 2
      Sept. 5-9, 12-16, 19-23, 26-30
      Oct. 3-7, 10-14, 17-21, 24-28, 31-Nov. 4
      Nov. 7-11, 14-18, 21-25, 28-Dec. 2
      Dec. 5-9, 12-16, 19-23, 26-30
  - Scripts, 1939
    - The Goldbergs (Box 18)
      Jan. 2-6, 9-13, 16-20, 23-27, 30-Feb. 3
      Feb. 2-10 (not used), 6-10, 13-17, 20-24, 27-March 3
      Mar. 6-10, 13-17, 20-24, 27-31
      Apr. 4-7, 10-14, 17-21, 24-28
      May 1-5, 8-12
    - The Goldbergs (Box 19)
      May 15-19, 22-26, 29-June 2
      June 5-9, 12-16, 19-23, 26-30
      July 3-7, 10-14, 17-21, 24-28, 31-Aug. 4
      Aug. 7-11, 14-18, 21-25, 28-Sept. 1
      Sept. 4-8, 11-15
    - The Goldbergs (Box 20)
      Sept. 18-22, 25-29
      Oct. 2-6, 9-13, 16-20, 23-27, 30-Nov. 3
      Nov. 6-9, 13-17, 20-24, 27-Dec. 1
      Dec. 4-8, 11-15, 18-22, 25-29
    - Special subjects
      - Auditions (Box 20)
        America's children, April
        Sunshine Inn, Za Zu Pitts, July
      - Campbell Playhouse - Counsellor at Law, Jan. 6 (Box 20)
  - Scripts, 1940
    - The Goldbergs (Box 21)
      Jan. 1-5, 8-12, 15-19, 22-26, 29-Feb. 2
      Feb. 5-9, 12-16, 19-23, 26-March 1
      Mar. 4-8, 11-15, 18-22, 25-29
      Apr. 1-5, 8-12, 15-19, 22-26, 29-May 3
      May 6-10, 13-17, 20-24, 27-31
    - The Goldbergs (Box 22)
      June 3-7, 10-14, 17-21, 24-28
      July 1-5, 8-12, 15-19, 22-26, 29-Aug. 2
      Aug. 5-9, 12-16, 19-23, 26-30
      Sept. 2-6, 9-13, 16-20, 23-27, 30-Oct. 4
      Oct. 7-11, 14-18
    - The Goldbergs (Box 23)
      Oct. 21-25, 28-Nov. 1
      Nov. 4-8, 11-15, 18-22, 25-29
      Dec. 2-6, 9-13, 16-20, 23-27, 30-Jan. 3, 1941
    - Special subjects (Box 23)
      House of Glass, for T.V. - May 1940
  - Scripts, 1941
    - The Goldbergs (Box 23)
      Jan. 6-10, 13-17, 20-24, 27-31
      Feb. 3-7, 10-14, 17-21, 24-28
      2, 1942Mar. 3-7, 10-14, 17-21, 24-28
    - The Goldbergs (Box 24)
      Mar. 31-April 4
      Apr. 7-11, 14-18, 21-25, 28-May 2
      May 5-9, 12-16, 19-23, 26-30
      June 2-6, 9-13, 16-20, 23-27, 30-July 4
      July 7-11, 14-18, 21-25, 28-Aug. 1
      Aug. 4-8, 11-15, 18-22, 25-29
    - The Goldbergs (Box 25)
      Sept. 1-5, 8-12, 15-19, 22-26, 29-Oct. 3
      Oct. 6-10, 13-17, 20-24, 27-31
      Nov. 3-7, 10-14, 17-21, 24-28
      Dec. 1-5, 8-12, 15-19, 22-26, 29-Jan 2, 1942
    - Kate Hopkins (Box 25)
      Apr. 7-11, 14-18
    - Kate Hopkins (Box 26)
      Apr. 21-25, 28-May 2
      June 9-13, 16-20, 23-27, 30-July 4
      Aug. 4-8, 11-15, 25-29
      Nov. 3-7
    - Kate Hopkins (Box 27)
      Nov. 10-14, 17-21, 24-28
      Dec. 1-5, 8-12, 15-19, 22-26, 29-Jan. 2, 19428
      Spot announcements
  - Scripts, 1942
    - The Goldbergs (Box 27)
      Jan. 5-9, 12-16, 19-23, 26-30
      Feb. 16-20, 23-27
      Mar. 2-6, 9-13, 16-20, 23-27, 30-April 3
      Apr. 6-10, 13-17
    - The Goldbergs (Box 28)
      Apr. 20-24, 27-31
      June 1-5, 8-12, 15-19, 22-26, 29-July 3
      July 6-10, 13-17, 20-24, 27-31
      Aug. 3-7, 10-14, 17-21, 24-28, 31-Sept. 4
    - The Goldbergs (Box 29)
      Sept. 7-11, 14-18, 21-25, 28-Oct. 4
      Oct. 5-9, 12-16, 19-23, 26-30
      Nov. 2-6, 9-13, 16-20, 23-27, 30-Dec. 4
      Dec. 7-11, 14-18, 21-25, 28-Jan. 1, 1943
    - Kate Hopkins (Box 30)
      Feb. 2-6, 9-13, 16-20, 23-27
      Mar. 2-6, 9-13, 16-20, 23-27, 30-Apr. 3, 1943 Special subjects Listen America Jan. 4, 1942 The Treasury Star Parade- Treasury Dept.,
      Aug. 11, 1942 Victory Front
      Nov. 23-27, 1942
  - Scripts, 1943
    - The Goldbergs (Box 30)
      Jan. 4-8, 11-15, 18-22, 25-29
      Feb. 1-5, 8-12, 15-19, 22-26
      Mar. 1-5
    - The Goldbergs (Box 31)
      Mar. 8-12, 15-19, 22-26, 29-Apr. 2
      Apr. 5-9, 12-16, 19-23, 26-30
      May 3-7, 10-14, 17-21, 24-28, 31-June 4
      June 7-11, 14-18, 21-25, 28-July 2
      July 5-9, 12-16
    - The Goldbergs (Box 32)
      July 19-23, 26-30
      Aug. 2-6, 9-13, 16-20, 23-27, 30-Sept. 3
      Sept. 6-10, 13-17, 20-24, 27-Oct. 1
      Nov. 1-5, 8-12, 15-19
    - The Goldbergs (Box 33)
      Nov. 22-26, 29-Dec. 3
      Dec. 6-10, 13-17, 22-24, 27-31
    - Special subjects (Box 33)
      Auditions - Potash & Perlmutter, Oct. 20, 1943
      Mr. Dunninger Program, Nov. 7
      Goldbergs - Special Night Show, Feb. 8
      What Price Victory, Apr. 12
  - Scripts, 1944
    - The Goldbergs (Box 33)
      Feb. 7-11, 14-18, 21-25, 28-Mar. 3
      Mar. 6-10, 13-17, 21-24
    - The Goldbergs (Box 34)
      Mar. 27-31
      Apr. 3-7, 10-14, 17-21, 24-28
      May 1-5, 8-12, 15-19, 22-26, 29-June 2
      July 3-7, 10-14, 17-21
    - The Goldbergs (Box 35)
      July 24-28, 31-Aug. 4
      Sept. 4-8, 11-15, 18-22, 25-29
    - The Goldbergs (Box 36)
      Nov. 6-10, 13-17, 20-24, 27-Dec. 1
    - Special subjects (Box 36)
      Auditions - Ma Ma Talks, Dec. 13, 1944
      Double or Nothing, June 2, 1944
      Guess Who, June 3, 1944
      Ivriah Luncheon, May 23, 1944
      V-Day Script, Sept. 19, 1944
  - Scripts, 1945
    - The Goldbergs (Box 36)
      Feb. 5-9, 12-16
    - The Goldbergs (Box 37)
      Feb. 19-23, 26-Mar. 2
      Mar. 5-9, 12-16, 19-23
    - Special subjects (Box 37)
      Name You Will Remember, by William Lang
  - Scripts, 1946
    - Special subjects (Box 37)
      Audition - The Goldbergs, Dec. 6
  - Scripts, 1947
    - Special subjects (Box 37)
      Audition - Penny, Jan. 21
  - Scripts, 1948
    - Special subjects (Box 37)
      Audition - The Goldbergs, T.V., 1948
      Whistle, Daughter, Whistle, by Ernest Kinoy
  - Scripts, 1949
    - The Goldbergs (Box 37)
      Jan. 17, 31
      Mar. 7, 14, 21, 28
      Apr. 4, 11, 25
    - The Goldbergs (Box 38)
      May 2, 9, 23, 30
      June 6, 13, 27
      Aug. 29
      Sept. 5, 12, 19, 26
      Oct. 3, 7, 10, 17, 24, 31
      Nov. 7, 14, 21
    - The Goldbergs (Box 39)
      Nov. 28
      Dec, 2, 4, 12, 16, 19, 23
    - Special subjects (Box 39)
      Broadway Talks Back, ANTA Program, 1949
      Red Feather U.S.A., Oct. 15, 1949
  - Scripts, 1950
    - The Goldbergs, T.V. (day and night programs) and radio, arranged by T.V. date; see below for just radio scripts. (Box 39)
      Jan. 2, 9, 16, 23, 24, 30
      Feb. 6, 13, 20, 27
    - The Goldbergs, T.V. (day and night programs) and radio, arranged by T.V. date; see below for just radio scripts. (Box 40)
      Mar. 6, 13, 20, 27
      Apr. 3, 10, 17, 24
      June 5, 12, 19, 26
      Sept. 25
      Oct. 2
    - The Goldbergs, T.V. (day and night programs) and radio, arranged by T.V. date; see below for just radio scripts. (Box 41)
      Oct. 9, 16, 23, 30
      Dec. 4, 11, 18, 25
    - The Goldbergs, Radio only (Box 41)
      Jan. 6, 13, 20, 27
      Feb. 4, 11, 18, 25
      Mar. 4
    - The Goldbergs, Radio only (Box 42)
      Mar. 11, 18, 25
      Apr. 1, 8, 15, 22, 29
      June 2, 10, 17, 24
  - Scripts, 1951
    - The Goldbergs, T.V. shows (Box 43)
      Jan. 1, 8, 15, 22, 29
      Feb. 5, 12, 19, 26
      Mar. 5, 12, 19, 26
      Apr. 2, 9, 16, 16, 23, 30
      May 7, 14, 21
    - The Goldbergs, T.V. shows (Box 44)
      May 28
      June 4, 11, 18
      July 3, 10
    - Special subjects (Box 44)
      Anti-defamation League, B'nai Brith, Dec. 13, 1951
      Big Show, Tallulah Bankhead, 1951
  - Scripts, 1952
    - The Goldbergs, T.V. shows (Box 44)
      Feb. 4-8, 11-15, 18-22 (2 folders), 25-29, (2 folders)
      Mar. 3-7 (2 folders), 10-14 (2 folders), 17-21 (2 folders), 24-28 (2 folders)
    - The Goldbergs, T.V. shows (Box 45)
      Mar. 31-Apr. 4 (2 folders)
      Apr. 7-11 (2 folders), 14-18, 21-25, 28-May 2 (2 folders)
      May 5-9 (2 folders), 12-16, 19-23, 26-30
    - Special subjects (Box 45)
      Anti-defamation League of B'nai Brith, May 11, 1952
      Big Show, Tallulah Bankhead, Feb. 24, 1952
  - Scripts, 1953
    - The Goldbergs, T.V. shows (Box 46)
      July 17, 24, 31
    - House of Glass, T.V. shows (Box 46)
      Oct. 23, 30
    - Special subjects (Box 46)
      The Goldbergs - Guild Filming "Rosie Nose" Oct. 27, 1955
  - Scripts, 1954
    - The Goldbergs (Box 47)
      Apr. 13, 20, 27
      May 4, 11, 18, 25
      June 1, 8, 15, 22, 29
      July 6, 13, 20, 27
      Aug. 3
    - The Goldbergs (Box 48)
      Aug. 10, 17, 24, 31
      Sept. 7, 14, 21, 28 (2 folders)
      Oct. 5, 12, 19
    - House of Glass (Box 48)
      Feb. 5, 12
    - Special subjects (Box 48)
      Hearts & Hollywood - The Elgin Hour, Nov. 30, 1954
      Motherhood and Brotherhood, Nov. 1954
  - Scripts, 1955
    - The Goldbergs - T.V. - Guild Filming (Box 48)
      Script #, Air date:
      1, Sept. 22
      2, Oct. 6
      3, Nov. 17
      4, Dec. 1
      5, Oct. 20
      6
      8, Oct. 13
      9, Sept. 29
      10, Nov. 3
      11, Nov. 10
      12, Jan. 19, 1956
      13
    - The Goldbergs - T.V. - Guild Filming (Box 49)
      14, Nov. 24
      15
      16, Dec. 8
      17, Jan. 5, 1956
      18, Dec. 29
      19
      Jan. 12, 1956
      20, Feb. 16, 1956
      21, Jan. 26, 1956
      22, Feb. 9, 1956
      23
      Rosie's Nose, undated
    - Special subjects (Box 49)
      Ed Murrow- interview
      Home Show- NBC Cookbook, Nov. 1, 1955
      Mind Over Mama- Elgin Hour, May 31, 1955
      Week Day Radio- Margaret Truman, Dec. 16, 1955
  - Scripts, 1956
    - The Goldbergs- T.V.-Guild Filming (Box 49)
      24, Mar. 8
      25, Feb. 23
      26, Mar. 1
      27, Mar. 22
      28, Apr. 5
      29, Mar. 15
      30, Mar. 15
      31 through 36, undated
    - The Goldbergs- T.V.-Guild Filming (Box 50)
      37 through 39, undated
    - Special subjects (Box 50)
      Molly Goldberg and the United Way
  - Scripts, 1957
    - Special subjects (Box 50)
      Academy Nominations, Silvers-Berg Spot, Feb. 1957
      Arthur Murray
  - Scripts, 1958
    - None
  - Scripts, 1959
    - None
  - Scripts, 1960
    - Special subjects (Box 50)
      Ed Sullivan Show, April 18
  - Scripts, 1961
    - Mrs. G. Goes to College (Box 50)
      April undated
      June 28
      July 3, 11, 23, 27
      Aug. 15, 16, 23, 30
      Sept. 20, 26
      Oct. 3, 4, 5, 20, 26, undated
      Nov. 6, 7 (2 folders)
    - Mrs. G. Goes to College (Box 51)
      Nov. 15, 20, 29
      Dec. 18, undated
      "The Conference, " undated
      Story Outlines: "The Big Thirst," "Excelsior"
    - Special subjects (Box 51)
      Aunt Sarah
      SOS, Aug. 18
  - Scripts, 1962
    - The Gertrude Berg Show (Box 51)
      Jan. 11, 15, 17, 31
      Feb. 5, 14
  - Special subjects, miscellaneous
    - Comic script, 1944; scripts for promotion (Box 51)
    - Cookbook, Molly Goldberg, mockup copy (Box 51)
    - Interviews
      - Ben Bernie's Show, Oct. 12, 13, 1936 (Box 51)
      - Cavalcade of Stars, Oct. 18 (no year) (Box 51)
      - Dunninger Show, May 31, 1944 (Box 51)